Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics Advisory council records, 1931-2013.
New York State College of Home Economics Advisory council records, 1931-2013.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Home Economics Advisory council records, 1931-2013.
23-21-2794
New York State College of Home Economics Advisory Council.
2.7 cubic feet.
Minutes, correspondence, biographical information, and published reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes, correspondence, biographical information, and annual reports of the Advisory Council.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes, correspondence, biographical information, and annual reports of the Advisory Council.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Home Economics; Cornell University.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. 1930-1939
Box 1- Folder 1
Series II. 1940-1949
Box 1- Folders 1,2
Series III. 1950-1959
Box 1- Folders 2-8, 23
Series IV. 1960-1969
Box 1- Folders 8-18, 24-33, 35, 36; Box 2- Folders 1,2
Series V. 1970-1979
Box 1- Folders 18-20, 33, 34, 36, 37, 39-41; Box 2- Folders 3-7
Series VI. 1980-1989
Box 1- Folders 20-22, 37-40; Box 4- Folders 1-6
Series VII. 1990-1999
Box 4- Folders 5-13; Box 5- Folders 1-11
Series VIII. 2000-2010
Box 6- Folders 1-4
Series IX. Advisory Council Members
Box 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. 1930-1939
  - Minutes of the Council, 1931, 1941-1943, 1945, 1947, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. 1940-1949
  - Minutes of the Council, 1931, 1941-1943, 1945, 1947, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series III. 1950-1959
  - Minutes of the Council, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series IV. 1960-1969
  - Minutes of the Council, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1968, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, Membership Info, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Advisory Council- Biographical Information, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Advisory Council- Correspondence concerning members, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Advisory Council Annual Reports, 1962-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Reports to the Board of Trustees concerning Activities of the College and School Councils, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Reports to the Board of Trustees concerning Activities of the College and School Councils, 1967-1968, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Transcripts of Advisory Council Meetings, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Fall
  - Transcripts of Advisory Council Meetings, 1969-05, 1969-11 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series V. 1970-1979
  - Minutes of the Council, 1968, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Advisory Council Annual Reports, 1962-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dan's Reports to the Advisory Council, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Reports to the Board of Trustees concerning Activities of the College and School Councils, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Reports to the Board of Trustees concerning Activities of the College and School Councils, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Advisory Council- Reports and Presentations, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Advisory Council- Speeches, memoranda, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Advisory Council- Photo, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series VI. 1980-1989
  - Minutes of the Council, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Reports to the Board of Trustees concerning Activities of the College and School Councils, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Reports to the Board of Trustees concerning Activities of the College and Schools Councils, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Advisory Council- Reports and Presentations, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Advisory Council- Speeches, memoranda, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report
    - Report to Board of Trustees Concerning Activities of the College and School
    - Councils
    - Implications for Cooperative Extension and the Land-Grant Universities
  - 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report
    - Report to Board of Trustees Concerning Activities of the College and School
    - Councils
    - Future of the Cornell Cooperative extension
    - Correspondence of the Advisory Council
    - Human Ecology Program in Aging Draft
  - 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Minutes of the Council- October
    - Overview of the Statutory Colleges of Cornell
    - Alumni Giving- 5 year history
    - Early decision report
    - Advisory Council Background Materials
    - Departmental Updates
    - Extension Update
  - 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report
    - Minutes of the Council- May and October
    - Report to Board of trustees concerning Activities of the College and School
    - Councils
    - College of Human Ecology-Securing the Future Report
    - Departmental Updates
    - Human Ecology Facts
    - Campaign Planning Update
  - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Council Member Bios
    - Annual Report
    - Minutes of Council April and October
    - Departmental Updates
    - Criteria for quality extension programs
    - Resources for Research: How Should they be Allocated
    - Resources for Research: Responses
  - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Cornell University Alumni Study
    - Background Materials for the Press
    - Affirmative Action Plan
    - Statutory Fund Flows
    - Media Coverage
- Series VII. 1990-1999
  - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Council Member Bios
    - Annual Report
    - Minutes of Council April and October
    - Departmental Updates
    - Criteria for quality extension programs
    - Resources for Research: How Should they be Allocated
    - Resources for Research: Responses
  - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Cornell University Alumni Study
    - Background Materials for the Press
    - Affirmative Action Plan
    - Statutory Fund Flows
    - Media Coverage
  - 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report
    - Minutes of the Council April and October
    - Council Member Bios
    - Study of Post-Graduate Activities
  - 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cooperative Extension 4-year Work Plan
    - Overview of the Cornell Life Course Institute
    - College Academic Plan
    - Correspondence
    - Graduate study in Nutrition
    - Particulars: News about faculty and staff
  - 1992-10 (Box 4, Folder 8A)
    - Orientation Packet
  - 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Annual Report
    - Minutes of the Council-April
    - Council Member Bios
    - Using Information Technology to Enhance Career Services
    - Council for the Cornell Cooperative Extension System Bios
    - Evaluation and Recognition of teaching
    - Excerpts from Annual Report
    - Departmental Updates
    - Correspondence
    - Media Coverage
  - 1993-10 (Box 4, Folder 9A)
    - Orientation Packet
  - 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Minutes of the Council
    - Council Recommendations
    - Annual Report
    - Departmental Updates
    - Advisory Council Bios
    - Cooperative Extension Highlights
    - Strategic Planning Report
  - 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
    - Studies
    - Media Coverage
    - Particulars: News about faculty and Staff
  - 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Minutes of the Council
    - Annual Report
    - Strategic Planning Report
    - Advisory Council Bios
  - 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Studies
    - Media Coverage
    - Correspondence
  - Orientation Packet, 1994-10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Orientation Packet, 1995-10 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Minutes of the Council- April and October
    - Council Member Bios
    - Budget
    - Materials from the Professor Baer "Ideological Diversity"
    - Controversy
    - Correspondence
    - Media Coverage
  - Minutes of the Council, 1996-04, 1996-10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Orientation Packet, 1996-10 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Information, 1997-04 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Information, 1997-11 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Information, 1998-04 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Information, 1998-09 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Information, 1998-10 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Information, 1999-04 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series VIII. 2000-2010
  - Meeting Packet, 1999-10 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Packet, 2000-03 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Packet, 2000-10 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Packet, 2001-04 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Packet, 2001-10 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Packet, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Packet, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Packets, 2004-1006 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Packets, 2007-03, 2007-09 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Packets, 2008-03, 2008-09 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Packets, 2009-04, 2009-09 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Meeting Packet, 2013-10 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Packet, 2015-03 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Series IX. Advisory Council Members
  - Booklets including biographical information on Human Ecology Advisory Council Members, 1964-2005 (Box 3)
  - pamphlets listing Cornell University's Advisory Councils and Boards 1958, 1960-1961, 1966, 1977, 1979-1989, 1992, 1995-2003, 1958-2003 (Box 3)